# Curriculum Vitae of Francois A Scholtz

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Full Names : Francois Andre

Surname : Scholtz

Location : Potchefstroom, North West, SA

Email address : fascholtz1982@gmail.com

Telephone/cell number : +27 83 244 3825

Linkedin : francois-scholtz-64597834

#### **PROFFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

With over 18 years' experience within the energy industry and electricity sector. I have worked directly with National and Provincial and Local Government departments to assist municipalities with their electricity business. Also focusing on industries such as Mining (Gold and Uranium) and deals with cross boarder supplies for Botswana Power Corporation.

#### **EDUCATION DETAILS**

Institution:North West UniversityQualification:Bachelor of ScienceCourse of Study:Information Technology

Date of Graduation : 04/2021

Modules covered : Computer Science, Accounting,

Business Management, Statistics,

Mathematics

Achievement : GPA: 3.15 (year 2)

Golden Key International Honours

Society Member 2020

Institution : Danville Secondary School

Qualification:Grade 12Date of Graduation:12/2000

Modules covered : English, Afrikaans, Mathematics,

Physics, Biology, Accounting

Achievement : M-Score: 1200 – 1439

Endorsement (Bachelor's pass)

# **EDUCATION DETAILS (Additional)**

Institution : Energy Training Foundation

Qualification : Certificate

Course of Study : Introduction to Energy Management

Date of Graduation : 2014

Modules covered : Fundamentals - Energy Management

Achievement : Competent

Institution : Eskom Centre of Excellence

Qualification : Certificate

Course of Study : Introduction to Project Management

Date of Graduation : 2017

Modules covered : Fundamentals – Project

Management (Part 1 and 2)

Achievement : Competent

## **SKILLS DETAILS**

Institution : North West University

Skills Acquired : C++, Java, C#, SQL, Python, MS

Projects, QM Solver, SDLC, Report

Writing,

Institution : Eskom Holding SOC Ltd

Skills Acquired : Basic electricity, Telephone skills,

Ethics, Electricity pricing,

Presentation skills, Facilitator

training, MS Projects Basic, Disability

etiquette awareness, Gender

awareness, Diversity management,

First aid and Firefighting - level 1

# **WORK EXPERIENCE DETAILS**

Institution : Eskom Holdings SOC Ltd

Position : Energy & Revenue Loss Officer

Employment period : 04/2020 to Date

**Duties:** 

Ensure the coordination and execution of energy and revenue loss management plan
of the Operating Unit.

- Co-ordinate auditing and verification of installations in liaison with field and metering staff
- Initiate the recovery of energy and revenue losses.
- Initiate the prosecution process.
- Stakeholder Management.

Achievement : Competent

Institution : Eskom Holdings SOC Ltd

Position : Key Customer Relations Officer

Employment period ` : 10/2011 to 3/2020

**Duties:** 

Advice and technical support.

- · Administrative and information systems support.
- Tariffs/incentives.
- Forecasting.
- Sales.
- Customer service.
- Credit revenue and credit management

Achievement : GM Awards Winner - 2017

Customer Service Best Achievers – 2018

Institution : Eskom Holdings SOC Ltd

Position : Customer Acquisitions Officer

Employment period : 03/2009 to 09/2011

Duties:

- Quotations and connections services.
- General supervision.
- Accountable for customer data.
- Handle generic service activities.
- Build a relationship between the customer base and "Eskom" via personal proactive interventions.
- Manage all measurement and meter related tasks.
- Manage vending and prepaid activities.

:

# **WORK EXPERIENCE DETAILS (Continued...)**

 Institution
 :
 Eskom Holdings SOC Ltd

 Position
 :
 Service Agent – Area Office

Employment period : 11/2008 to 2/2009

**Duties:** 

- Direct the daily customer service activity operations.
- Responsible for customer data.
- Handle generic service activities.
- Build a relationship between their customer base and "Eskom" via personal proactive interventions.
- Conducts all conventional measurement and meter related tasks.
- Processes and conducts credit revenue and credit management processes.
- Perform vending and prepaid activities.
- Processing quotations and connections activities.

:

Institution:Eskom Holdings SOC LtdPosition:Assistant Officer – Area Office

Employment period ` : 10/2004 to 10/2008

Duties:

- Maintains the daily customer service activity operations.
- Responsible for existing or new customer data.
- Handle generic service activities.
- Build a relationship between their customer base and Eskom" via personal proactive interventions.
- Provide product information and advice, customised for specific (new and existing) customers' needs.
- Handling quotations and connections activities.

Achievement :

Institution : Eskom Holdings SOC Ltd
Position : Contact Centre Service Agent

Employment period : 08/2003 to 09/2004

**Duties:** 

- Handling inbound interactions.
- Handling back office activities (Non-technical dispatch and follow ups).
- Handling multi-media activities and outbound (proactive customer interaction) campaigns.
- General customer interaction and service improvement.
- Supports marketing, sales and customer service processes.
- Vending prepaid and easy pay.

Achievement : Various Employee of the Month

# **WORK EXPERIENCE DETAILS (Continued...)**

Institution : Eskom Holdings SOC Ltd

Position : Call Centre Service Agent (Temp)

Employment period ` : 09/2001 to 7/2003

#### Duties:

- Handling inbound interactions.
- Handling back office activities (Non-technical dispatch and follow ups).
- Handling multi-media activities and outbound (proactive customer interaction) campaigns.
- General customer interaction and service improvement.
- Supports marketing, sales and customer service processes.
- Vending prepaid and easy pay.

#### Achievement

:

### **REFERENCES**

Institution : Eskom Holdings SOC Ltd

Reference : Abram Tumane

Contact : 083 627 5937